<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Making Data Science Count</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations at the TN STEM Education Research Conference</title>
      <link>/post/presentations-at-the-tn-stem-education-research-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/presentations-at-the-tn-stem-education-research-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Making Data Science Count research group has two presentations at the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tntech.edu/education/stem/tennessee-stem-education-research-conference.php&#34;&gt;TN STEM Education Research Conference&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosenberg, J. M.,&amp;amp; Lishinski, A. (January, 2020). &lt;em&gt;Measuring what matters in-the-moment: An experience sampling approach to understanding the development of interest in computer science&lt;/em&gt;. Presentation at the 14th Annual Tennessee STEM Education Research Conference. Cookeville, TN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makingdatasciencecount.com/img/lishinski-rosenberg-sultana-2020-tn-stem.pdf&#34;&gt;View the poster here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosenberg, J. M., Hodge, L., Aydeniz, M., Schmidt, A. Lishinsli, A., Rich, K., Longnecker, J., Mann. M., &amp;amp; Sadovnik, A. (January, 2020). &lt;em&gt;A survey of teachers and administrators regarding the implementation of new K-8 computing education standards in Tennessee&lt;/em&gt;. Presentation at the 14th Annual Tennessee STEM Education Research Conference. Cookeville, TN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1A_DEyNaAjz5d2lbSdlwZ6unEAz96S7vtc4nNxnzjWMo/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;View the presentation slides here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R with 7th-grade science students (highlighted in Flowing Data!)</title>
      <link>/post/using-r-with-7th-grade-science-students-highlighted-in-flowing-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/using-r-with-7th-grade-science-students-highlighted-in-flowing-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A blog post on [Using R With 7th-Grade Science Students[(https://joshuamrosenberg.com/post/2019/11/13/using-r-with-7th-grade-science-students/)] was recently highlighted in the widely-read data visualization blog Flowing Data. A link to the post is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://flowingdata.com/2019/11/26/teaching-r-to-7th-graders/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is related to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makingdatasciencecount.com/project/ms-data-sci/&#34;&gt;this project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning three NSF-funded projects</title>
      <link>/post/beginning-three-nsf-funded-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/beginning-three-nsf-funded-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joshua Rosenberg will be beginning three NSF-funded projects this fall. They are
described in this post for the University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Department of
Theory and Practice in Teacher Education &lt;a href=&#34;https://tpte.utk.edu/2019/10/22/rosenberg-awarded-national-science-foundation-grants-to-further-computer-science-education/&#34;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the descriptions of the projects from the
newsletter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1937700&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34;&gt;Understanding the Development of Interest in Computer Science: An Experience Sampling Approach&lt;/a&gt; is a two-year project that builds on Rosenberg’s dissertation research about how students develop an interest in computer science. Rosenberg’s dissertation research utilized an experience sampling method in which study participants were surveyed with short questions delivered via cell phones at regular intervals throughout the course of their learning during out-of-school summer STEM programs.  This project uses a similar methodological approach in an undergraduate context. The $350,000 grant will support a postdoctoral scholar and a graduate research assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1923509&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34;&gt;CS for Appalachia: A Research-Practice Partnership for Integrating Computer Science into East Tennessee Schools&lt;/a&gt; is a two-year project led by Lynn Hodge, STEM education professor. The project is focused on developing a research-practice partnership among researchers, teachers and administrators to address challenges related to teaching computer science at the elementary level. Building upon the shared vision developed within the research-practice partnership, the $250,000 grant includes opportunities for K-5 teachers to engage in professional development about the Tennessee computer science standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=1920796&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34;&gt;Advancing Computational Grounded Theory for Audiovisual Data from STEM Classrooms&lt;/a&gt; is a three-year collaborative project among faculty at the University of Tennessee, Knoxville; Middle Tennessee State University (MTSU); and the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign (UIUC). The project is led by Christina Krist, UIUC assistant professor of curriculum and instruction. This project is focused on developing a new research methodology that uniquely combines two approaches: interpretative human-driven coding and newer machine learning techniques, also known as artificial intelligence. The aim is to use audio-visual data from STEM classrooms to study the kinds of teaching and learning of most interest to educational researchers rather than simply what can be studied using machine learning.The $1.3 million dollar grant will support a postdoctoral scholar at MTSU and graduate research assistants at UIUC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
