<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Making Data Science Count</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joshua M. Rosenberg (PhD, Michigan State University) is an Assistant Professor of STEM Education at the University of Tennessee, Knoxville. His research focuses on how learners think of and with data, particularly in science education settings. Dr. Rosenberg tries to understand how practices such as creating, representing, and modeling data create new opportunities for learning how to use data to pose and answer questions about scientific phenomena. In addition to how learners think of and with data, Dr. Rosenberg is also interested in student engagement across a range of STEM learning environments and the use of technology in education, particularly for teacher professional development. As a part of this work, Dr. Rosenberg makes use of quantitative methods, such as multi-level models for analyzing data collected through the experience sampling method, and newer approaches, such as social network analysis to analyze teachers’ conversations on social media.
Dr. Rosenberg teaches classes in science and STEM education, educational technology, and research methods. In his classes, Dr. Rosenberg aims to involve students in authentic practices from the field of study. For example, in teacher education classes, this plays out through giving students opportunities to both participate in as well as plan and enact activities focused upon engaging in scientific and engineering practices. In graduate-level classes, Dr. Rosenberg focuses on scholarly practices, particularly critiquing and contributing to ongoing conversations about educational policy and practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homepage: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuamrosenberg.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://joshuamrosenberg.com&lt;/a&gt;
CV: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jmichaelrosenberg.com/rosenberg-cv.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://jmichaelrosenberg.com/rosenberg-cv.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/jrosenberg.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/alishinski/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/alishinski/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/aschmidt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/aschmidt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anthony Schmidt is a PhD student in evaluation, statistics, and measurement (ESM), part of the Educational Psychology and Counseling Department. His research interests are varied and include international students, higher education, climate change and education, quantitative methods, and data visualization. Anthony also works full time as a data visualization research at the College and University Professional Association for Human Resources (CUPA-HR).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/aschmidt.jpg&#34; style = &#34;transform: rotate(270deg)&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/jlongnecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/jlongnecker/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/mmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/mmann/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/osultana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/osultana/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
